We see that we live in a circumstance
إننا نرى بأننا نعيش في ظرف
where there is mundane, inanimate lifeless things, matter,
يوجد فيه أشياء دنيويه، جامده، لا حياة فيها، مواد،
and then there are conscious, spiritual beings.
ويوجد آيضاً كائنات روحانيه واعيه.
[God Has Senses]
‫[الرب لديه إحساس] … ‬
So, when we deal with the aspect of consciousness,
لهذا وعندما نتعامل مع جانب الوعي،
consciousness never exists independently of personality.
فالوعي لا يتواجد أبداً مستقلاً عن الشخصيه.
It cannot exist absent of personality.
لا وجود له من دون وجود الشخصيه.
So we see, here are the many conscious beings.
هكذا نرى العديد من الكائنات الواعيه،
We were talking about this earlier today,
كنا نتحدث عن هذا في وقت سابق اليوم
if (I gave the example) I see someone,
وأعطيت هذا المثل، إذا رأيت شخصاً …
look at all the people in this room,
اُنظر إلى كل الأشخاص في هذه الغرفه،
they have two eyes, a nose, two ears and a mouth.
لديهم عينين، أنف، اذنين، وفم.
So, I can, without becoming a research scholar,
لهذا، يمكنني، من دون أن أكون باحث أو أديب
scientist, or any such thing,
أو عالم أو أي شيء من هذا القبيل،
or with advanced degrees in education,
أو بدرجات مرتفعه من التعليم،
I can assume that your mother, your father,
أن افترض أن والدتك أو والدك
they had two eyes, two ears, a nose, a mouth,
لديهم عينين واذنين وفم،
more or less.
بكل بساطة.
It’s safe for me to assume that.
يمكن أن تفترض هذا بكل أمان.
So when I see all these many beings
لذلك، عندما أرى كل هذه الكائنات
who possess these different types of characteristics,
التي يمتلكن هذه الخصائص المختلفه،
I could make a case and say,
يمكنني أن أبني قضيه و أقول
“Well, the original source of all such beings
"حسناً، المصدر الأصلي لمثل كل هذه الكائنات
must be similar. Someone with eyes, ears, you know …
يجب أن يكون مماثلاً. شخص له عينين واذنين …
who can see, touch, taste, smell, feel.”
باستطاعته أن يرى و يلمس و يذوق و يشم و يشعر."
We see in this world observable characteristics,
إننا نرى في هذا العالم خصائص يمكن ملاحظتها،
and these people who have these abilities.
و هؤلاء الناس الذين لديهم هذه القدرات
They’re searching for something beautiful to see,
يبحثون عن شيء جميل ليروه،
for someone beautiful to see,
عن شخص جميل ليروه،
for someone beautiful to touch, to hold, to interact with.
عن شخص جميل ليلمسوه، ليحضنوه، ليتفاعلوا معه.
They like to hear beautiful sounds,
إنهم يحبون أن يسمعوا أصوات جميله،
taste pleasing substances …
ليتذوقوا أشياء لذيذة.
These are just normal things
هذه هي أشياء عاديه
that everyone likes to do.
التي يحب كل شخص أن يقوم بها.
So I could understand, the original source
لهذا يمكنني أن أفهم بأن المصدر الأساسي
of all these types of beings who enjoy these things,
لكل هذه الأنواع من الكائنات الذي يتمتعون بهذه الأشياء،
must also have those kind of tendencies:
يجب أن يكون له هذه الأنواع من الميول:
to see, hear, taste, touch, smell, feel;
ليرى، يسمع، يتذوق، يلمس، يشم، ويشعر.
in other words, to interact with others
أو بمعنى آخر، أن يتفاعل مع الآخرين
in a loving, affectionate way,
بحب و بحنان،
as people are apt to do in this world.
مثل ما يفعل الناس في هذا العالم.